how many of you have often prayed that
prayer Lord forgive me for my failures
forgive me for self often getting in the
way I want to invite you to pray with me
today as uh we are preparing to hear a
message a word from the Lord that I
believe will be a powerful
blessing to you so let's pray Heavenly
Father we're asking today Lord that you
would please speak to us in a very
special way Lord let your word be
glorified
today and may those that are watching
those that are listening may they
understand the
power of your
love and the power of prayer we ask this
in Jesus name amen amen we are going to
be talking today about the power of
prayer and in fact
as we go to the screen you will see that
we're going to be looking at a case
study for this subject of prayer a case
study from The Book of Revelation does
prayer really work that's the question
on the table today does prayer really
work and yes you read that right we're
going to be looking at the seven
trumpets of Revelation that is going to
be our case study and I just want to ask
if you have ever asked yourself or even
wondered aloud man does prayer really
work I want you to check this out
because as we begin our study today
we're going to go to the book of uh
Matthew and we're going to see something
very powerful here remember Jesus is in
the Garden of Gethsemane he is about to
be crucified and he's got several of his
disci disciples with him and he's asking
them to to pray with him but they keep
falling
asleep and so Jesus comes back to them
several times and you read this in
Matthew 26 verse 41 where he says watch
and pray that you enter not into into
temptation the spirit indeed is
willing but the flesh is weak the spirit
is willing but the flesh is weak and I
want you to understand that these words
spoken by Jesus are crucial words we
need to understand that we may desire to
do the right thing but unless we are
fortified with
prayer the
Flesh in one sense he's saying the flesh
is weak but in another sense he's saying
the flesh is strong and if we don't
submit to prayer if we don't commune
with our heavenly father if we don't
commune with Jesus the power of the holy
spirit will not work through us to
overcome the flesh put a one in the chat
if you're following so far this is why
the Bible tells us about the armor of
God in the book of Ephesians I want you
to notice it with me with me the book of
Ephesians we're going to go to Ephesians
chapter 6 and note with me beginning
with verse 11 the Bible says put on the
whole armor of God that you may be able
to stand against the Ws of the
devil for we wrestle not against flesh
and blood but against principalities
against Powers against the rulers of the
darkness of this world against spiritual
wickedness in high
places wherefore take unto you the whole
armor of God that you may be able to
stand withstand in the evil day and
having done all to stand therefore
having your loins G about with truth and
having on the breastplate of
righteousness and your feet sought with
the preparation of the gospel of peace
reading
on above all take the shield of Faith
wherewith you shall be able to quench
all the fiery darts of the wicked and
take the helmet of salvation and the
sword of the spirit which is the word of
God now I want you to focus in on this
verse right
here Verse 18 says praying always
always with all prayer and supplication
in the spirit and watching there unto
with all perseverance and supplication
for All
Saints the Bible here is telling
us that prayer is an essential weapon
for the people of God which brings us
back to the question does prayer really
work does prayer re do we have any
evidences that prayer actually works
evidence in history that prayer actually
works and this is why beloved we're
going to take a look at the Book of
Revelation for our case study to answer
this question now I need you to
understand
something this whole sermon
today is to bring to you
the power of one
verse now y'all are not going to see
that verse till the very end of the
sermon but everything that I'm about to
share with you from this point forward
is is to amplify is to set the stage for
you to see the power behind this one
verse this is going to give you hope
just start putting it in the chat if
you're excited put a seven in the chat
this is going to give you hope this is
going to help you to see that yes God
does answer prayer and when you
understand all of that as the context
for this one verse it's going to change
everything for you so are y'all ready
let's go let's go we're going to the
Book of Revelation The Book of
Revelation and we're going to
go to chapter 8 verse two now we're
going to spend most of our time in the
Book of Revelation because we're going
to be dealing with the seven trumpets
found in Revelation chapter 89 10 and
11 and so beginning with Revelation
chapter 8 verse2 the Bible
says John speaking here says and I saw
seven angels which stood before God and
to them were given seven
trumpets and another angel came and
stood at the altar having a golden
sensor and there was given unto him much
incense that he should offer it with the
prayers of All Saints upon the golden
altar which was Before the
Throne the Bible continues on and the
smoke of the incense which came with the
prayers of the Saints ascended up before
God out of the Angel's hand
verse five and the angel took the sensor
and filled it with fire of the Altar and
cast it into the Earth and there were
voices and thunderings and Lightnings
and an earthquake all right so here's
what I want y'all to get so far okay the
picture that we see in Revelation
chapter 8 which is an introduction to
the seven trumpets shows this incense
rising up out of an angel's hands with
the prayers of the Saints Saints and
whatever is happening here it involves
the prayers of the Saints and now listen
carefully in
answer to the prayers of the Saints we
see fire coming down from God out of
Heaven are y'all with me so far in this
picture in this scene we see prayers of
the Saints going up and we see fire
falling in answer to the prayers of the
Saints put a one in the chat if you're
with me so
far all right I see you all following me
now let's go ahead and move on so what
we want to do here is ask ourselves a
simple question first of
all what what do trumpets symbolize in
the Bible what were they used for
because we need to understand this if
we're going to understand the
significance of the blowing of the
trumpets in Revelation chapter 8 there
are seven trumpets that are blown what
do these trumpets symbolize let's go
back to the screen and I want you to
note with me we're going to go to a
couple places to see this we'll go to
Revelation I'm sorry we'll go to Numbers
chapter 10 and verse two the Bible says
here God speaking instructing the
children of Israel and speaking through
Moses said this make thee Two Trumpets
of silver of a whole piece shalt thou
make them thou sh th that thou mayest
use them for the calling of the assembly
and for the journeying of the camps all
right so if I were to ask you what
according to numbers is the purpose of
the blowing of the trumpet your answer
would be oh Pastor the blowing of the
trumpet symbolizes it was a symbol it
was something used to call the people of
God together and to tell them to advance
to move forward okay so number one
please write this down if you're taking
notes the trumpet signify the children
of Israel continuing on their Journey
when the trumpet blew it was a a call to
move forward are y'all with me so far
all right so far so good let's go to the
next slide and I want you to notice here
Numbers Chapter 10:9 and if you go to
war in your land against the enemy that
oppresses you then shall you blow an
alarm with the trumpets and you shall be
remembered before the Lord your God and
you shall be saved from your enemies all
right so if you're taking notes you're G
to be writing down two things so far
number one trumpets symbolize God's
people moving forward and number two
trumpet symbolize God's people being
saved from their
enemies are y'all with me so far all
right excellent let's keep moving let's
keep moving we're going to go back to
the
screen and I want you to notice Joshua
chapter 6 verse5 which tells us yet
another story regarding trumpets this is
when they are Marching around Jericho
right and I want you to notice what
happens here in Joshua chapter 6
verse5 it shall come to pass that when
they make a long blast with the Ram's
Horn and when you hear the sound of the
trumpet all the people shall Shout with
a great shout and the wall of the city
shall
what fall down flat and the people shall
Ascend up every man straight way before
him so once again we're seeing here that
when the trumpets were blown one
particular story in the Old Testament
shows that when the trumpets were blown
the city of the enemies fell
let's put this together so far number
one trumpet symbolize moving forward
number two trumpet symbolize being saved
from your enemy number three trumpet
symbolize the enemy opposition
falling all right come on we got one
more one more we're going to go to the
Book of Judges chapter 7 this is the
story of Gideon yet another story
dealing with trumpets and you'll
remember that Gideon was told to go
forth with his 300 men they go forth to
fight the enemy they blow the trumpet
and notice with me Judges chapter 7: 21
they stood every man in his place round
about the camp and all the host ran and
cried and fled watch
this and the 300 blew the trumpets and
the Lord set Every Man's sword against
his fellow even throughout the
throughout all the host so what I want
you to see here is that when the
trumpets were blown not only did it
symbolize God's people moving forward
not only did it symbolize the enemies of
God's people falling before them but it
also symbolized that they would turn
their weapons upon
themselves please keep these things in
mind because you're going to see the
significance of this as we come to
understand what these seven trumpets in
the Book of Revelation are talking about
so now I want to ask you a
question because we we've got to figure
out okay when did this event happen when
is it that we can think of saints
praying in the Bible their prayers going
up and then Fire coming down in answer
to the prayers of the Saints and if
y'all are thinking you got the answer I
know you got it because this occurred on
the day of Pentecost come on y'all let's
go there let's go there I want y'all to
check this out we're talking about the
the power of prayer the Bible says in
Acts chapter 2 verse1 and when the day
of Pentecost was fully come they were
all with one Accord in one place and
suddenly there came a sound from Heaven
as of a rushing Mighty Wind and it
filled all the house where they were
sitting verse four or verse three and
there appeared unto them clothing
tongues like as of
fire and it sat upon each of them
what do you have here what do you have
going on you have saints praying you
have saints praying and as their prayers
are going up the response to their to
their prayers going up is
fire coming
down I need y'all to catch the
significance of this because what we're
about to
see is a chronological case study of God
God answering prayer now y'all remember
what happened right this is when the the
church is given the gift of
tongues because God has commissioned
them to take the gospel into all the
world so they have a mission they are
supposed to be moving forward say that
with me someone moving
forward with the
gospel now here's what's so significant
keep that in mind here's what is so
significant
because Peter stands up to preach on
this day of
Pentecost and if you remember he quotes
from a particular book remember they
think oh these guys are drunk what we
can't even what do they sing and then
Peter says hey we're not drunk notice
what he says here notice what he says
let's go back to the screen Peter quotes
from The Book of
Joel here is what he quotes
he says this is that which is spoke
which was spoken by the prophet Joel
listen to
this it shall come to pass in the last
days sayith God I will pour out my
spirit upon All Flesh and your sons and
your daughters shall prophesy and your
young men shall see visions and your old
men shall dream dreams and on my
servants and on my handmades I will pour
out in those days of my spirit and they
shall
prophesy and I will show wonders in the
heavens and signs in the earth beneath
blood and fire and Vapor of smoke the
sun shall be turned into darkness and
the moon into blood before the great and
notable day of the Lord come now let me
ask y'all a
question how many of you if you were
there on the day of Pentecost would have
been like Peter what are you talking
about we don't see any blood we don't
see the sun getting dark we don't see
any of this stuff what are you talking
about maybe as you read the verse now
you're asking the question why would
Peter be even quoting from The Book of
Joel what is so significant about this I
want you to note beloved how Joel
chapter two
begins this is the book that Peter is
quoting from under the inspiration of
the Holy
Spirit notice how the chapter that he's
quoting from
begins come on
y'all come on somebody somebody needs to
put a one in the chat for me if y'all
are catching
this the chapter begins blow ye the
trumpet in Zion and sound an alarm in my
Holy Mountain let all the inhabitants of
the land tremble for the day of the Lord
cometh for for it is nigh at hand a day
of darkness and of gloominess a day of
clouds and of thick Darkness as the
morning spread upon the mountains a
great people and a
strong there has not been ever the like
neither shall there be anymore after it
even to the years of many generations a
fire lock this in you guys lock this
in this is the chapter that Peter is
quoting from and this chapter is going
to explain to us that Peter was not
referring to literal blood and literal
Darkness he was saying something that he
was hoping would trigger the memories of
the people that he's talking to his own
people listen to what Joel chapter 2
goes on to
say a fire devoureth before them and
behind them a flame burneth the land is
as the Garden of Eden before them and
behind them a DE desolate Wilderness yay
and nothing shall Escape them what I
want y'all to catch is
this
Peter is warn he's telling them listen
Israel if you do not accept the
Messiah an army is coming to destroy our
nation that's why Peter is refering ing
back to Joel chapter 2 so the question
we need to ask is very simple what army
could Peter have possibly been talking
about this description of the sky being
darken and all these calamitous things
happening were were a description of the
coming destruction of Jerusalem put a
one in the chat if y'all are
Following come on there's something very
important this is key I need y'all to
get this let's go back to the screen and
and I want you to follow along so it
says that before them was like the
Garden of Eden but behind them the land
would be
desolate nothing shall Escape them verse
four the appearance of them is as the
appearance of horses and as Horsemen so
shall they run verse five like the noise
of Chariots upon the top of mountain
shall they leap like the noise of a
flame of fire that devour its stubble
and as a strong people set in battle
array so he is clearly talking about an
army that is coming
before their faces the people shall be
much pained all faces Shall Gather
Blackness they shall run like Mighty Men
they shall climb the wall like Mighty
Men of War they shall March everyone on
his ways and they shall not break their
ranks the Earth shall Quake before them
and the heaven shall tremble and the sun
and the moon shall be dark and the Stars
shall withdraw their signing and the
Lord shall utter his voice before his
array before his army for his Camp is
very great for he is strong that
executeth his word for the day of the
Lord is great and very terrible who can
abide it Joel 2:15 blow the trumpet in
Zion sanctify a fast call a solemn
assembly gather the people sanctify the
congregation assemble the elders gather
the children and those that suck the
breast let the bridegroom go forth out
of his chamber and the bride out of her
closet let the priests the Ministers of
the Lord weep between the porch and the
Altar and let them say spare thy people
oh Lord and give not thine Heritage to
reproach that the Heathen should rule
over them wherefor should they say among
the people where is their God Peter is
clearly warning here of a impending
Invasion a military Invasion but he's
using symbolic
language so in the Book of Joel chapter
2:20 he goes on to say but I will remove
from a far off from you the northern
Army and will drive him into a land
Barren and desolate with his face toward
the East sea and his hinder part toward
the utmost sea and his stink shall come
up and his ill saor shall come up
because he has done great things and I
will restore to you the years that the
Locust has eaten the cankerworm and the
caterpillar and the Palmer worm my great
Army which I sent among you for a nation
is come up upon my land strong and
without number whose teeth are as a
teeth of lion and he has the cheap teeth
of a great Lion now what is God saying
here God is basically saying listen if
my people repent I will drive this Army
from
you so he's laying out Peter is
reminding Israel he's saying to Israel
listen something is coming Upon Our
Nation and if we repent if we pray
remember the trumpets if we pray and
seek the Lord's
face he will turn this thing away from
our
nation what
happens what happens we
know in Joel chapter
1119 the Bible says in the Lord oh Lord
to thee will I cry for the fire has
devoured the pastures of the Wilderness
the flame has burned all the trees of
the field he's talking about the
impending destruction of Jerusalem he's
going back to Joel and he's bringing all
these things to the people's mind and
then notice this did Israel
listen to the warnings given by the
early church the early followers of
Christ they did not and in fact in Acts
chapter 7:58 we find the stoning of the
first Christian martyr Steven the Bible
says Bible says in Joel or acts 7:58 and
he said behold I see the heav Heavens
opened and the son of man standing at
the right hand of God then they cried
out with a loud voice and stopped their
ears and ran upon him with one Accord
and they cast him out of the city and
stoned him and the witness laid down
their feet at a young man's feet or laid
down their clothes at a young man's feet
whose name was Saul y'all get the story
right this is where Stephen is stoned
and in effect Israel has
rejected the pleading
of
God they stoned Steven calling upon God
and and they stoned Steven calling upon
God and saying Lord receive my
spirit
and we
have the
first Christian martyr being martyred
by God's Own professed
people they've deed declared themselves
enemies of the early
church setting this Foundation I need
y'all to catch this now we're going back
to the first trumpet all right so notice
with me what trumpet number one says
first trumpet Revelation 8 ver7 the
first Angel sounded and there followed
hail and fire mingled with blood and
they were cast upon the earth and the
third part of the trees was burnt up and
all the green grass was burnt up
now I'm GNA ask you a
question we already saw that trumpets
symbolize first of all the trumpets are
blown in answer to what put it in the
chat for me
please the trumpets are blown in answer
to the prayers of the Saints
that's number
one so when the trumpets are blown we
can expect several things number one it
is
God telling his people to do
what to go forward number two it will
represent the fall of the enemies of
God's people are y'all with
me number three it'll represent the
enemies of God's people turning their
weapons upon one another and watch this
all of this in answer to
prayer so let's ask a question y'all
let's ask the question I want you to
watch this who is the first enemy of the
church the early church who is the first
enemy of the early church because if we
can get the answer to that then we know
what this first trumpet is dealing
with Beloved the first enemy of the
church was Israel the professed people
of God they were the ones persecuting
and attempting to stop the spread of the
Gospel the the nation that rejected the
Messiah not all individuals in there but
the nation that rejected the Messiah
they became the the the primary opposers
of the
Gospel now you'll remember that Jesus
used the symbol of a fig tree remember
what the Book of Joel said y'all
remember the Book of Joel is talking
about a coming Army that's going to
desolate that's going to burn down
everything in front of it and please
come back with me to that first trumpet
look and the first Angel sounded and
there followed hail and fire mingled
with blood and was cast upon the earth
and the third part of the trees was
burnt up and all the green grass was
burnt up I need y'all to see this
because Jesus used the Fig Tree to
symbolize
Israel when he saw a fig tree in the way
he came to it and found nothing thereon
but leaves only and he said unto it let
no fruit grow on thee henceforth Forward
Forever and presently the Fig Tree
withered away and when the disciples saw
it they marveled saying how soon is the
Fig Tree withered away I need y'all to
catch this
everyone in answer to
prayer in answer to prayer in in in an
effort to to to to get the gospel out
the early church it's trying to get the
gospel to go into all the world but his
own professed people are standing as an
an obstacle before them and what does
God do in answer to prayer he says we're
moving them out the
way we're going to move this nation out
the way in order for God's message to
advance The Book of Ezekiel chapter 20
verse 46 son of man set thy face toward
the South and drop Thy word toward the
South and prophesy against the forest of
the south field and say to the forest of
the South hear the word of the Lord
thus sayi the Lord God behold I will
Kindle a fire in thee it shall devour
every Green Tree in thee and every dry
tree the Flaming Flames shall not be
quenched and all the faces of the South
to the north shall be burned therein God
was trying to let me say it this way
that this first
trumpet is the
punishment of God upon the enemy enemies
of the
Gospel the Bible says in Isaiah 40:6 the
voice said cry and he said what shall I
cry all flesh is grass and all the
goodliness thereof is the is as the
flower of the field the grass withereth
and the flower fadeth because the spirit
of the Lord bloweth upon it surely the
people is as grass this is the first
trumpet beloved it is the fall of the of
Jerusalem in 70 AD it is the destruction
of Jerusalem and watch this who
destroyed
Jerusalem it was the Romans the same two
groups that came together to be a party
to Christ's crucifixion end up turning
their swords on one another and the
Romans destroy Jerusalem and in this
destruction the Christians who were
Christian Jews Christians were able to
escape and and take the gospel advance
the
gospel and you want to ask the question
does prayer
work does prayer
work Beloved the answer is yet we have
the evidence
listen
prayer is what allowed the early
Christian Church to advance past their
enemy in order to spread the go
gospel come on let's keep moving let's
keep moving the fall of Jerusalem watch
this the fall of Jerusalem's enemies the
fall of Jerusalem and their enemies turn
their sword turning their sword upon one
another is the Fulfillment of that first
trumpet what about the second
trumpet the Bible says here and the
second Angel sounded and as it were a
great Mountain burning with fire was
cast into the sea and the third part of
the sea became blood and and the third
part of the creatures which were in the
sea had and had life died and the third
part of the ships were destroyed now
remember we have already seen here that
these trumpets are not talking about
literal fire and literal blood this is
symbolic language and the pace was set
for us when Peter himself quoted from
The Book of
Joel and and what we're seeing here is
that the first trumpet Was the removal
of the first Obstacle of the early
church which was the Jewish
Nation so now we got to ask ourselves a
simple question which is this who is the
second enemy of the people of God after
Jerusalem has been moved out the way and
the gospel is going forward who now is
the primary enemy of the people of god
let's go back to the screen I want to
show you something here very quickly
about mountains listen to this I want
you to see what a Mountain symbolizes in
the scriptures in Jeremiah 51:24 the
Bible says and I will Render unto
Babylon and to all the inhabitants of
Calia all their evil that they have done
in Zion in your sight say the Lord watch
this behold I am against thee o
destroying Mountain say the Lord which
destroy all the Earth and I will stretch
out mine hand upon thee and roll thee
down from the rocks and will make thee a
burnt Mountain so
please get this a burning Mountain
symbolizes a Fallen
Nation so you might ask okay pastor what
does this burnt mountain in this second
trumpet symbolize remember what we said
right if a trumpet if the blowing of the
trumpet represents the removing of God's
enemies then we know that all we got to
do is ask ourselves the question who was
the next enemy of the people of God and
that answer is the Roman Empire they
were persecuting God's people during the
early centuries of the of the church and
listen to this y'all because this is
absolutely mind-blowing watch this in
the Book of Matthew remember we had just
read Matthew 21 now in the morning as he
returned into the City and was hungry he
saw the fig tree right and came to it
and found nothing there on but leaves
only and said unto it let no fruit grow
on thee henceforth forever and presently
the fig tree with it away we already saw
that this fig tree was a symbol of
Jerusalem God was saying look Jerusalem
has borne no fruit it's going to be
destroyed watch
this and when the disciples saw it they
marveled saying how soon is the Fig Tree
withered away and watch what Jesus's
next words are oh
man watch what Jesus's next words are
y'all remember what the second trumpet
is a burning Mountain m is cast into the
sea symbolizing the fall of a kingdom of
a power of a Nation what is Jesus's next
words after they Marvel Jesus said watch
this Jesus answered and said unto them
verily I say unto you if you have faith
and doubt
not you shall not only do this which is
done to the Fig Tree but also if you
shall say unto this mountain be thou
removed and be thou cast into the sea it
shall be
done yeah somebody needs to put a five
in the chat if y'all are catching
this the second look this fig tree being
cursed is the symbol of Jerusalem being
removed out of your way so that the
gospel can advance the disciples was
like whoa they don't understand what
Jesus is saying but they're like whoa
look at the tree and Jesus says verily I
say to you if you have faith and say to
this mountain be thou removed it shall
be done and listen y'all we got to ask
ourselves a question what were the
prayers of the Saints during this time
period where they were being persecuted
by Rome father we want to get this
message out into the world but the there
is an obstacle before us and the Lord
says I've heard your prayer trumpet
number two is blown listen
y'all
Rome was brought down by prayer I just
need to stop right here for a second
y'all some now y'all been like where you
going with this pastor listen to me
you're asking the question is prayer
powerful is prayer effective listen
y'all
Rome was brought
down by prayer y' y'all are trying to
stop the spread of the Gospel I'm going
to remove you out of the
way Rome that burning mountain is cast
into the sea you know that Seas
represent peoples Nations multitudes and
tongues and that's exactly what Rome
broke down into peoples Nations
multitudes and
tongues Barbarian
tribes beloved God answers pre if I were
to stop the sermon right here I would
say to you right now
God answers prayers but we're not done
yet because there are more trumpets to
come let's go back let's go back and
again we're going to ask ourselves a
question we're going to ask ourselves a
question who is the second enemy of the
church and we saw the answer to that was
the Roman Empire so watch this the fall
of Jer the fall the first trumpet
represented the fall of Jerusalem the
second trumpet the fall of the Roman
Empire and by the way how did Rome fall
yes they turn their swords upon one
another they turn their swords upon one
another oh
man y'all need to understand
this y'all need to understand
this
listen Rome Falls and now we have a
third trouble
so the third trumpet reads like this and
the third Angel sounded and there fell a
great star from Heaven burning as it
were a lamp and it fell upon the third
part of the rivers and upon The
Fountains of waters and the name of the
star is called wormwood and the third
part of the waters became wormwood and
many men died of the waters because they
were made bitter so now we got to ask
ourselves a question okay H and beloved
listen I want y'all to see how this is
broken down right because now we got to
ask ourselves a question okay so if
we're following the pattern the first
enemies of Rome would represent of of
the church would represent Jerusalem
that city was removed out of the way the
second enemies of church would represent
Rome that city was moved God they were
moved out of the way so that the message
could
advance so now we got to ask ourselves
one simple question who after the fall
of Rome who became the new en enemies of
God's
people and you you are right I can
pretty much guess what y'all about to
put in the chat right because it was the
papal system it was the
Roman Catholic Church that
began persecuting the people of God who
refus to acknowledge the pope as God who
refused to do Penance all those things
they began to be attack they are now the
new enemy so now we know listen to me
now we know that trumpet three trumpet
four trumpet five trumpet six at least
those next four trumpets are going to be
dealing with the
downfall or we might even say the deadly
wounding of this
church now listen if y'all are have not
follow me in prophetic understandings
before and you're hearing this for the
first time you might be like how papacy
what go back and watch some my other
videos but for those of you who are who
who are familiar I'm not going to take a
whole lot of time to explain this but I
need y'all to catch this these next
trumpets are all dealing with bringing
about the or exposing if you will the
papal system for what it is which would
ultimately lead to its
fall
so come on let's break this down very
quickly so we're going to go back to the
screen we're going to go back to the
screen who is the third enemy of the
church it is a religio political power
it called the papacy papal Rome and I
want you to note this third trumpet then
is a punishment upon apostate
Christianity the apostate Church of the
Dark Ages now you say how how because
remember let's go back to that trumpet
it says that the word the waters uh this
um the third Angel sounded and there
fell a great star from Heaven burning as
it were and it fell upon the parts of
the rivers and the fountains of waters
that's where we drink from that's where
people drink from and what's Happening
Here Is God is
poisoning the religious aspects of the
church if you will remember this is a
religio political power what God is
doing doing here is he's Leading Men to
see something is the matter with the
water that this church is offering it's
causing men to die people were beginning
to have their eyes open to the apostasy
and the error being taught within this
system and this is where we get the
beginning of the Reformation people
coming on the scene like w cliff and
others who are like wait a minute
something's wrong here this would be the
think of the wal denans this is where
we're going to find that that people
began to realize something is wrong with
the remember water is drinking water is
a symbol of the gospel God is now
revealing there's something wrong with
this drinking water he's exposing the
religious Corruption of this system it's
the same thing listen to me watch this
let go back to the screen and and I want
you to know here I want you to
know
uh behold Amos chapter 811 behold the
days come say the Lord God that I will
send a famine in the land not a famine
of bread nor thirst for water but of
hearing the words of the Lord and they
shall Wander from sea to Sea and from
the north even to the east they shall
run to and fro to seek the word of the
Lord and shall not find
it in those days shall the fair virgins
and the young men faint for
thirst so this third trumpet as it were
signified an Awakening if you will
something is wrong with this system that
is claiming to serve God the same thing
with the fourth with the fourth angel or
the fourth trumpet the fourth Angel
sounded and the third part of the sun
was smitten and the third part of the
moon and the third part of the Stars so
as that the third part of them was
darkened and the day Shone not forth
third part of it and the night likewise
in other words God is doing the same
thing here he's bringing he's allowing
the darkness of this system to be
revealed so that men would begin to say
wait a minute something's wrong with
this system in fact in Isaiah chapter 8
verse chapter 5 verse2 it says woe unto
them that call evil good and good evil
that put Darkness for light and light
for darkness that put bitter for sweet
and Sweet for
bitter woe unto them
what God is doing here is he's bringing
he's revealing the corruption the
spiritual corruption and bankruptcy of
this system so that God's people could
see and go wait a minute something's
wrong here they are not who they profess
to be this system is not what it
professes to be and this was would in
part lead to the deadly wounding of this
papal
system
the these are the roots of the
Protestant Reformation and what is God
saying I want you to advance I want you
to move forward I'm going to move this
system out of your way so that you can
take the gospel into the whole world now
I want you to check this out because
there's still three other
trumpets there's still three other
trumpets I want you to note with me want
you to note with
me
Revelation Revelation chapter 9 now
remember here's what we just saw the
papacy is a relig political system
trumpets number three and four are
revealing the corruption within the
religious aspect of this system but now
trumpets number five and six are going
to deal with the political or military
aspect of this system note with me
Revelation 9 verse one and the fifth
angel sounded and I saw a star fall from
Heaven onto the Earth and to him was
given the key of the bottomless pit and
he opened the bottomless pit and there
arose of smoke out of the pit as the
smoke of a great furnace and the Sun and
the air were darkened by reason of the
smoke of the pit and there came out of
the smoke Locust upon the Earth and unto
them was given power as the Scorpions of
the Earth have power
and it was commanded them that they
should not hurt the grass of the earth
they should not hurt the grass of the
earth neither any green thing neither
any tree but only those men which have
not the Seal of God in their foreheads
now let me pause for a second let me
just come back here for a second so I
ask yall a question and we're almost
there we're almost done we're we're
almost to that verse that is going to
blow your
mind but let me ask you a
question if we know that in the Book of
Joel and army just like this was
described and it's described in a sense
of God bringing punishment upon those
who are opposing his message so we know
that in Revelation chapter nine this
Army of locust is not really an army of
locust it's an army of people but now
the question is who are these Army of
people coming for
who are they coming for who is this Army
of
people we know that the enemies of God's
people during this time represent the
pap system so God is going to allow God
is going to bring another group of
people to begin conflict with the
papacy in order to
give the reform
time to get the message
out now I don't know if you know this
history or
not but we're talking about the Muslim
armies we're talking about the
Crusades I want you to understand that
the
papacy was at a point where they were
trying to totally Stamp Out the
Protestant Reformation but just around
this time they began being attacked by
Muslim armies and they had to turn their
attention and I should say this all this
was a war that was going on for some
time but they ultimately had to turn
their entire attention and resources to
deal with the Muslim threats and Martin
Luther himself
said that were it not for the Muslim or
the Turkish power engaging with the
papacy protestantism would have been
wiped out
now this is trumpet number five beloved
and trumpet number six which is talking
about the same Army in two different
phases we're not going to spend time to
go into that because this message today
is not so much about prophecy being
fulfilled this message today is to help
you understand something absolutely
mindblowing that the gospel is where it
is in the world today because of the
prayers of the Saints God God in answer
to the prayers of the Saints
removed Jerusalem in 70 AD removed the
Roman Empire in the thir Century ad
removed the papacy after that 1260 year
period known as a dark ages gave it a
deadly wound to give God's people time
to read and understand that final
message which was to go into all the
world all these trumpets these six
trumpets beloved represent present God
answering the prayers of the Saints by
the
way the Turkish Empire the Muslim Army
the Muslim empire what was it a religio
political power so what does God do he
takes one religio political power to war
against another religio political power
in essence they're turning their swords
on one another giving God's people
time giving the Protestant Reformation
time to grow and to
advance beloved we can trace it through
history how prayer literally moved
Nations so now I'm G ask y'all a
question we're get we're right about
there y'all we are right about there I'm
gonna ask you yall a question we're not
going to go through we're not going to
go through all the rest of the sixth
trumpet but I just need y'all to see
something here right I need y'all to
catch
this let's go back to the
screen and I want you to check this
out on we're GNA we're just gonna let's
go let's go let's go here we go chapter
number five and
six the rise of
Islam and their attack upon the
papacy now please know
this within this seventh trumpet within
this sixth trumpet we also have the
French Revolution which is in essence
what brought about the deadly wound of
the papacy Revelation 11 is found right
there right after Revelation 9
Revelation 10 it's all in the
trumpets so watch this y'all ready
here's the seventh angel and the seventh
angel sounded and there were great
voices in heaven saying the kingdom of
this world are become the kingdoms of
our Lord and of his Christ and he shall
reign for forever and ever I got a
question to ask you if if the seventh
trumpet brings about the kingdom of Our
Lord then the question is who is the
final enemy of God's
people who are the final enemies of
God's people because where they are the
seventh trumpet brings about there fall
and if we just saw that the seven
trumpet the kingdoms of this world are
become the kingdoms of Our Lord then
guess what it is the kingdoms of this
world that are the enemies of God's
people they are the F everybody comes
together to fight against the people of
God those that keep the Commandments of
God and have the testimony of Jesus in
fact we could let me restate it this way
who are the final enemies of God's
people
Babylon
Babylon watch this y'all watch
this the the first trumpet the fall of
Jerusalem the second trumpet the fall of
Rome the third trumpet the fall of the
papacy the fourth trumpet I'm sorry the
third fourth fifth and sixth trumpet the
fall of the papacy we know that the
papacy receiv received a deadly wound
but that deadly wound would be healed
they're going to come back and be and be
that mystery Babylon revived along with
apostate protestantism and the entire
world the seventh trumpet beloved is the
ultimate fall of
Babylon prayer brought down the fall of
Jerusalem prayer brought down the fall
of Rome prayer brought down the fall of
the papacy prayer is going to bring down
the fall of Babylon now I got to ask you
a question what mountain stands in your
way I know no my sermon is about to end
I I need I needed to demonstrate to
you the power of the prayers of the
Saints rising up and God answering
through these trumpets God answering
saying my people I'm I want you to
advance my people I'mma move the
obstacles out of your way now I'm GNA
ask you a question again what
obstacle stands in your
way per perhaps the biggest obstacle
that stands in our
way is
self but what I want you to see beloved
is that if
God can move Nations through
prayer he can move you out of your
way yes he
can yes he can are you mightier than a
nation were you bigger than Rome did you
have more power than
Rome you're not mightier than a
Nation Beloved God can move not here is
a text y'all here is a
text here it
is Micah
7:19 he will turn again he will have
compassion upon us he will
subdue our
iniquities can y'all put a Steven in the
chat for me
please he will subdue if he subdued
Jerusalem if he subdued Rome if he
subdued the papacy if he's going to
subdue Babylon at the end of time moving
these enemies out of the way as a result
of the prayers of the Saints do you not
think that he can subdue your iniquities
he can move move your sins just as he
cast that burning Mountain into the sea
can he not take your sins and cast it
into the depth of the
sea beloved if God is able if God
through prayer if God through the
prayers of the Saints moved
Nations what
sin in your
life can he not
move what sin in your life can he not
forgive and cast it into the sea what is
what obstacle in your life can he not
remove so that you may
Advance with the
purpose of being a light in your
neighborhood a light in your family a
light in the world
does prayer
work I just need you to look at the
history we have
evidence not anecdotal
evidence biblical prophetical historical
evidence that God answers
prayers that prayers can move
mountains and bring about the removal of
Nations and so if prayer can do all that
beloved what can prayer not do in your
life what can prayer not
do regarding those
obstacles that are before
you so my wife likes to call these
trumpet pray prayers cuz she's heard me
say this before and and once it clicked
for her she was like ah I'm going to
start praying trumpet
prayers let's start praying trumpet
prayers
believing I want you to understand
that these prayers were going up over
time it wasn't like Just One Day prayer
and then God answered they had to
persevere in
prayer beloved let us persevere in
prayer let us begin to pray trumpet
prayers if that's your desire put that
one in the chat help me to pray trumpet
prayers and help me to believe that when
I pray Lord forgive me of my sin remove
this Sin from me that God does it help
me to know that when I pray Lord self is
an obstacle in my way right now please
remove self let us have the faith that
just as God said you can say to this
mountain be thou moved into the sea so
God can move the obstacle that stops you
from coming closer to
him Heavenly Father we thank you
Lord for showing
us how much you are
invested in the gospel advancing to the
whole
world and that anything that stands in
the way of the Salvation of souls you
will
remove
Lord teach us to have that
Faith to say to the mountains before us
be thou removed into the sea and believe
that they shall be
moved grant us the
patience and the faith to use the weapon
of prayer and believe in the power of
prayer thank you Lord for speaking to
our hearts
today in Jesus name we pray amen